userinterviews.com 2019-12-17

# Privacy Policy

Effective Date: November 20, 2019

‍

User Interviews (“User Interviews,” “we,” or “us”) respects your privacy. Our website helps connect organizations and individuals seeking to conduct market research (“Researchers”) with people interested in participating in market research (“Participants”). This privacy policy (“Policy”) describes how we collect, use, and disclose information about Researchers, Participants, and other website visitors (collectively, “Users”) in connection with our website and the online services provided through us(collectively, the “Services”). This policy does not apply to information that you submit directly to third parties, including the organizations and individuals with which you connect on the Services.

#####  **Information We Collect About You**

We collect Personal Information and Other Information about Users in connection with the Services. For the purposes of this Policy, “Personal Information” is information that does or can be used to identify you, such as your email address or phone number. “Other Information” is any information we collect that is not Personal Information.

We may combine Personal Information with Other Information, in which case we will treat the combined information as Personal Information. We also may combine information that we have about you with additional information that we,Researchers, or other third parties collect in other contexts—such as our communications with you via email or phone, your responses to project screening questions, your customer service records, or any feedback provided by a Researcher.In those circumstances, we will treat the combined information as Personal Information. 

 ** _Information About Participants_**

If you are a Participant, we may collect the following Personal Information about you:

  * First name
  * Last name
  * Phone number
  * Email address
  * Birth date
  * Password

We may also collect Other Information about you, including but not limited to:

  * City, state, and country
  * Gender
  * Household income
  * Ethnicity
  * Marital status
  * Level of education

In addition, Researchers may ask you to fill out screening questions to help them select Participants. We collect your answers to those screening questions and use that information as described in this Policy. We also collect messages you send to us through our “Contact Us” or other messaging features, as well as the messages that you send to other Users through our Services. In addition, we may ask you follow-up questions and collect your answers to such questions.  

NOTE:  please do not submit any Sensitive Information (defined below) to or through the Services in response to any question or request from a Researcher.  

In certain situations, Participant accounts in the Services are created by Researchers to enable those Participants to participate in projects and research of a particular Researcher only, and not projects or research of any other Researcher (“Researcher-Affiliated Participants”). In these cases, Researchers and/or Researcher-Affiliated Participants enter information about Participants directly into the Services for use solely in connection with the applicable Researcher’s project(s). Such Participants do not have individual accounts separate from the Researcher, unless such Participants create separate, independent accounts with us. All of our collection and use of your information in this context is on behalf of the Researcher, and not on our own behalf. All references to Participants in this Policy also apply to Researcher-Affiliated Participants, except where a separate section for Researcher-Affiliated Participants is provided. 

**_Information About Researchers_**

If you are you a Researcher, we may collect the following Personal Information about you:

  * First name
  * Last name
  * Company name
  * Email address
  * Phone number
  * Password

‍

If you are a Researcher, we may collect information about you and your research project(s), including but not limited to:

  * Internal project name
  * Public project title
  * Project description
  * Number of participants
  * Study length
  * Study and interview type
  * Participant incentive and amount
  * Desired characteristics of participants
  * Participant screening questions
  * Schedule

When required, we will collect your credit card or other payment information. We use third-party payment service providers to process payments on our behalf, and as a result we do not ourselves store your credit card number or other payment information.

In addition, we collect messages you send to us through our “Contact Us” or other messaging features. We also collect messages you send to other Users through our Services.

 ** _Information About All Users_**

We collect information about Users automatically through the Services. This may include information such as your IP address and domain name, your Internet service provider, the date and time of your visit, your use of the Services during your current session and over time (including the pages you view and the files you download), the URLs from the websites you visit before and after navigating to the Services, your computer’s operating system and browser type, your software and hardware attributes (such as device IDs, device OS, and device type), search keyword and search engine, and your general geographic location (e.g., your city, state, or metropolitan region). Such information may be considered Personal Information under certain applicable law. We collect such information using the following technologies:  

  * **Server Logs.**  When you use the Services, we automatically receive and record certain information from your computer (or other device) and your browser. To obtain such information, we may use server logs or     applications that recognize your computer and gather information about its online activity.
  * **Cookies.**  We also use cookies. Cookies are small files that are stored on your computer (or other device) by your web browser. A cookie allows the Services to recognize whether you have visited the Website before and may store user preferences and information. If you are concerned about having cookies on your computer, you can set your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being set, allowing you to decide whether to accept it. You can also delete cookies from your computer. However, if you     choose to block or delete cookies, certain features of the Services may not operate correctly.  For more     information about the cookies that we use, please visit our cookie policy (<https://www.userinterviews.com/cookies>)
  * **Pixel tags.**  The Services or the emails that you receive from us may use an application known as a “pixel tag” (also known as a “clear gif” or “web beacon”). A pixel tag is an electronic file that usually consists of a     single-pixel image. It can be embedded in a web page or in an email to transmit information, which could include Personal Information. For example, it allows an email sender to determine whether a user has opened a particular email.
  * **Collaboration with Third-Party Data Collectors.**  We may partner with certain third parties to collect, analyze, and use some of the information described above. For example, we may allow third parties to set cookies or use pixel tags or other tracking mechanisms (such as tags or scripts) on the Services or in email communications from us, or we may allow third parties to use an application software development kit (SDK) or a server-to-server connection to collect information, including device identifiers such as IDFA and Advertising ID. The information collected by third parties using these technologies may be used for a variety of purposes, including analytics, as described in the “Third-Party Analytics” section below.

In addition, we may offer you the ability to refer a friend to our Services. If you use this feature, we may ask you for information needed to contact the referral, such as your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend an email stating that you referred your friend. We may, from time to time, continue to send messages to your friend as a reminder of your invitation.  If your friend wishes to stop receiving these messages, your friend can follow the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of any message. By providing your friends’ names and email addresses, you represent that you have the authority to do so and that such individuals have consented to the disclosure of their information for these purposes.  

 **How We Use Your Information**

‍

 ** _Information About Participants._**

If you are a Participant, we use your information to:

  * Provide the Services to you, administer your account, fulfill the terms of any agreement you have with us, evaluate you for qualification to participate in projects, or respond to your requests. Note that any information you submit in response to Researcher screening questions or requests may be used by us to evaluate you for qualification to participate in projects and to provide the Services.  
  * Allow Researchers to consider and select Participants for their research projects. We may share with any Researcher any information that we have about you, including but not limited to your name; age; ethnicity; city, state, and country; gender; contact information; household income; marital status; level of education; and responses to their screening questions, and our follow-up questions.
  * Send you administrative communications related to the Services, including communications about projects for which you have applied or have been selected.
  * Send you marketing communications, in a manner consistent with your marketing preferences and applicable laws. If you wish to opt out of receiving promotional emails at any time, please click the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of the email. Please note that if you unsubscribe from promotional emails, you will continue to receive non-promotional administrative emails with information relevant to your     account and the operation of the Services.

 ** _Information About Researcher-Affiliated Participants._**

If you are a Researcher-Affiliated Participant, we use your information to:

  * Provide the Services to the applicable Researcher in accordance with such Researcher’s agreement with us.
  * Share any information that we have about you with the particular Researcher, but not with any other Researchers. 
  * Send you administrative communications related to the Services, including communications about projects for which you have been selected.

For information about how the applicable Researcher will use your information, please contact the applicable Researcher.  

**_Information About Researchers._**

If you are a Researcher, we use your information to:

  * Provide the Services to you, administer your account, fulfill the terms of any agreement you have with us, or respond to your requests.
  * Allow Users to view your research projects. All Users may be able to view your project’s public title, description, compensation, session length, study and interview type, screening questions, and general location. Depending on your preferences, participants who are confirmed for your research project(s) will be able to see such information as your first name and last name, company name, email address, and phone number.
  * Send administrative communications related to the Services, including communications about your research projects.
  * Send you marketing communications, in a manner consistent with your marketing preferences and applicable laws. If you wish to opt out of receiving promotional emails at any time, please click the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of the email. Please note that if you unsubscribe from promotional emails, you will continue to receive non-promotional administrative emails with information relevant to your     account and the operation of the Services.
  * Facilitate the processing of payments.

 ** _Information About All Users._**

For all Users, we use your information to:

  * Analyze use of the Services, and analyze our Users’ demographics and other information.
  * Improve our existing products and services or create new products and services.
  * Personalize your experience on our website.
  * Engage in analytics as described in the “Third-Party Analytics” section below.
  * Comply with legal and/or regulatory requirements, or protect our rights and interests.
  * Facilitate the processing of payments (if applicable).

 **How We Share Your Information**

We may share your information with the following third parties:

  * **Third-party service providers.**  We use third-party service providers to help us provide, manage, and improve the Services. These service providers may collect and/or use your information to assist us in achieving the purposes discussed in this Policy.
  * **Affiliates.**  We may share information with our corporate affiliates for the purposes described in this Policy.
  * **Other Users of the Services.**  We may share your information with other Users of the Services as described above in the section titled “How We Use Your Information.”
  * **Your direct sharing of information through the Services.**  The Services may enable you to share information, including Personal Information and Sensitive Information, directly through the Services. For example, the Services may contain messaging features that enable you to interact with or share content with other Users of the Services.
  * **Analytics.**  We may share your information with third parties to research and analyze our Users and to seek to broaden our User base.
  * **Third-party plugins and integrations**  The Services may integrate certain third-party plugins, widgets, or integrations (such as social media plugins). Even if you do not click on these plugins, widgets, or     integrations, they may collect information about you, such as your IP address and the pages that you view. They also may set and/or access a cookie or other tracking mechanism. Each plugin, widget, and integration     is governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it, and not this Policy.
  * **Facebook Custom Audiences and Similar Programs.**  We may partner with Facebook and other social media partners to deliver advertisements to our Users and third parties via the Facebook Custom Audiences program or a similar third-party program. In order to identify and reach our Users and similar audiences on     Facebook or another third-party service, we may share information such as an email address or phone number with Facebook or the other third-party service. If you would like to opt out of receiving advertisements from us through such programs based on your email address or phone number, please     send an email with the subject line “Unsubscribe from direct social media ads” that includes your name and contact information to support@userinterviews.com. For more information about custom audience     targeting and how to adjust your social media advertising preferences, please review the privacy policy of your social media provider.
  * **Legal purposes.**  We may disclose your information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to (i) comply with a legal obligation such as a judicial or governmental subpoena or     warrant; (ii) protect and defend our rights or property; (iii) act in urgent circumstances to investigate or protect the personal safety of users of the Services or the public; or (iv) protect against legal liability, prevent suspected fraud, or establish, protect, or exercise our legal rights.
  * **Financing, business transfers, and similar transactions.**  As we develop our business, we might sell or buy businesses or assets. In the event of a sale, merger, reorganization, dissolution, or similar event relating to     all or a portion of our business or assets, your information may be part of the transferred assets. We also may share information to facilitate the potential or actual financing, securitization, insuring, merger,     acquisition, sale, assignment, bankruptcy, or other disposal of all or part of our business or assets.
  * **De-identified or aggregated information.**  We may also share de-identified and aggregated information about Services Users, such as by publishing a report on trends in the usage of the Services or sharing aggregated information about historical survey matching results.

 **Sensitive Information**

Personal or Other Information related to your racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion or other beliefs, health or sex life, criminal background or trade union membership, and other similar information may be considered “Sensitive Information” under certain applicable law. We sometimes collect Sensitive Information when you create an account in the Services. For example, if you are a Participant, we may request that you provide information about your ethnicity. By entering such information, you consent and agree that we may use such information in accordance with this Policy. 

If you are a Participant, please do not submit Sensitive Information to or through the Services in response to any question or request from a Researcher.  

If you are a Researcher-Affiliated Participant, your applicable Researcher may ask you screener questions that involve Sensitive Information. The applicable Researcher is the controller of that information and we do not use it for our own purposes other than to provide the Services to the applicable Researcher as described in this Policy.

 **Third-Party Analytics**

We may partner with certain third parties to collect the information discussed above and to engage in analytics, auditing, research, and reporting. These third parties may use web logs, pixel tags, or other technologies, and they may set and access cookies on your computer or other device.

In particular, the Website uses Google Analytics, Mixpanel, and Hotjar to help collect and analyze certain information for the purposes discussed above. 

·       To opt out of Google Analytics, click here: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

·       To opt out of Mixpanel, click here: <https://mixpanel.com/optout>

·       To opt out of Hotjar, click here: <https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out>

For more information about how these third parties collect and use your information, please see their privacy policies.

 **“Do Not Track”**

Like many other websites, our Website does not respond to “do not track” browser headers.

 **Third-Party Links, Websites, Apps, and Communication Technologies**

Our website and the Services may contain links to and from websites and apps of other third parties. If you follow a link to any of these websites or apps, please note that these websites and apps, and any services that may be accessible through them, are operated and controlled by third parties and have their own privacy policies. A link to any third-party site does not imply that we endorse or accept any responsibility for the content or use of such site. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave the Services and to read the privacy policies applicable to such third-party websites and apps. Similarly, Researchers may survey or otherwise communicate with Participants via phone, email, videoconferencing, or other communication methods not provided, facilitated, or endorsed by us. These technologies have their own privacy policies and are not covered by this Policy. 

**Security**

We use commercially reasonable physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect your information against loss or unauthorized access, use, modification, or deletion. However, no security program is 100% secure, and thus we cannot guarantee the absolute security of your Personal or Other Information.

 **Data Retention**

We retain information for as long as reasonably necessary to deliver our Services to you or to fulfill the purposes described in this Policy or as required by law. For example, we may retain your information for as long as you maintain your User Interviews account so that you can participate in or post multiple research projects overtime.  If you are a Participant and deactivate your account, we will delete your Personal Information after 90 days.  If you are a Researcher and deactivate your account or end your agreement with us, we will delete all Researcher-Affiliated Participant Personal Information associated with your account after 90 days. However, we reserve the right to retain any information required under applicable law.

 **Your Choices and Access to Information**

You have the right and ability to edit your User Interviews account information on our Services at anytime by logging into and updating your account. You may access, amend, and/or request deletion of certain information to the extent permitted under applicable law. To make such requests and/or inquire about such rights, please send us an email at support@userinterviews.com. For your protection, we may only implement requests with respect to the information associated with the particular email address you use to send us your request, and we may need to verify your identity before implementing your request. We will attempt to comply with any reasonable requests for accessing, amending, or deleting your information.  

Researcher-Affiliated Participants:  If you are a Researcher-Affiliated Participant, please contact the applicable Researcher with requests related to your information. We are not a “controller” of the Personal Information of Researcher-Affiliated Participants, and will pass any requests along to the Researchers, but cannot respond to your requests directly. We do not control or own Personal Information of Researcher-Affiliated Participants, and only process such Personal Information on behalf of the Researcher with whom you are affiliated.  In such cases, we process Personal Information in accordance with our agreements with Researchers and to the extent necessary to comply with applicable law. To the extent instructed by a Researcher and in accordance with applicable law, we will reasonably assist a Researcher to comply with Participant requests by providing relevant information and support to the particular Researcher to enable it to comply with the request.

 **Children’s Privacy**

We do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 18 and do not target our Services to children under 18. If you are under 18, please do not use the Services. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children’s Internet usage and to help enforce this prohibition. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 18 has provided information to us, please contact us, and we will endeavor to delete that information from our databases.

 **Information for California Residents**

If you are a California resident, you have a right to request certain information with respect to the types of information we have shared with third parties for their direct marketing purposes, and the identities of those third parties, within the immediately preceding calendar year, subject to certain exceptions. All requests for such information must be sent to support@userinterviews.com. This same California law permits us to provide you, in response to your written request, with a cost-free means to choose not to have your certain information shared rather than providing the above described information. To that end, you may request that we do not disclose certain of your information to unaffiliated third parties for their own direct marketing purposes by contacting us by email at support@userinterviews.com.

If you are a California resident under 18 years of age and a registered user of our Services, you may request that we remove content and information that you post on our Services. To obtain removal of such content and information, please send us an email at support@userinterviews.com with a short description of the content or information you would like to have removed. Please be aware that such a request does not ensure complete or comprehensive removal of the content or information you have posted and that there may be circumstances in which the law does not require or allow removal even if requested.

 **Information for Users Outside the United States**

The information that we collect through the Website and in connection with the Services is transferred to and processed in the United States for the purposes described in this Policy. We may also subcontract the processing of such information to, or otherwise share information with, affiliates or third parties in the United States or countries other than your country of residence. The data-protection laws in these countries may be different from, and less stringent than, those in your country of residence. By using our Services or accepting our Policy, you expressly consent to such transfer and processing.

You may have the right, in accordance with applicable data protection laws: to request access to, rectification of, and/or erasure of your information; to seek restrictions on the processing of your information; to object to certain processing of your information; and to exercise a right of data portability.

Where any processing of information is solely dependent upon your consent, such as marketing to you, you have the right to withdraw such consent at any time.

Where you believe that we have not processed your information in accordance with the applicable data protection laws, you may lodge a complaint with the respective supervisory authority/data protection regulator.

The provision of information by you will be for contractual, marketing, or analytical purposes as referred to above. If we do not have access to such information from you, then we will not be able to undertake the above types of services for you.

We may withhold information where the search for that information would required is proportionate effort or have a disproportionate effect due to, for example,the cost of providing the information, the time it would take to retrieve the information, or how difficult it may be to obtain the information requested.

To inquire about or exercise your rights in accordance with applicable law, please contact us at [support@userinterviews.com](mailto:support@userinterviews.com).

 **EEA Residents**

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area, you have certain rights regarding our use of your Personal Information. Some of these rights, e.g., the right to be forgotten or the right to request that we transfer your Personal Information to another company, will only apply in certain circumstances. Generally, these rights will not be available if there is an outstanding agreement or ongoing business relationship between us, if we need that information to continue to provide the Services to you, if we are required by law to keep the information or if the information is relevant to a legal dispute.

UI is the data controller of Personal Information that you provide to us if you are a Researcher,Participant, User, or website visitor, but not if you are a Researcher-Affiliated Participant, and the purposes of our processing of Personal Information are described in this Policy, our Terms of Service and/or other commercial agreement you have entered into with us.  In this context, we process Personal Information on the following bases: (i) when the processing is necessary for purposes of our legitimate business interest in conducting our business. We take into account any risks to your fundamental rights and freedoms in assessing these purposes (including your right to privacy); (ii) when the processing is necessary for us to comply with our legal obligations; (iii) when you give us consent to process your Personal Information; and (iv) when such processing is necessary in order to enter into or perform a contract you have entered into with us, such as providing the Services.  We may also process Personal Information on other bases permitted by the GDPR and applicable laws.

If you are a Researcher-Affiliated Participant, we are a “processor” of your Personal Information only, and the purpose of our processing is to fulfill our contractual obligations with your respective Researcher.  

We have listed the rights you have over your Personal Information and how you can use them below. These rights are subject to restrictions under European data protection law and,subject to the exemptions in that law, may only apply to certain types of information or processing.

  * We need your consent for some of the ways we use your Personal Information, e.g., for marketing or processing special categories of information about you. You can remove that consent at any time.
  * You can ask us to confirm if we are processing your Personal Information and if we are, you can ask for access to that information and details about such processing.
  * You can ask us to correct your Personal Information if it’s wrong.
  * You can ask us to delete some of your Personal Information.
  * You can ask us to restrict how we use your Personal Information.
  * You can ask us to help you move some of your Personal Information to other companies.
  * You have a right to ask that we provide your Personal Information in an easily readable format to another company.
  * You can ask us to stop using your Personal Information, but only in certain cases.
  * You have the right to complain to the relevant supervisory authority.

You also have a right to object to us processing your Personal Information in certain circumstances.  You can ask us to stop processing your Personal Information at any time. In certain circumstances, we may not be able to do this or may not be required to do this. For example, if we have an ongoing business relationship, if we required by law to keep it, or if it is relevant to a legal dispute, then we may not stop processing your Personal Information.

You have the right to file a complaint concerning our processing of your Personal Information with your national data protection authority. If you are in the EEA, find your local DPA [<https://edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/board/members_en>].  If you are in the UK, the Information Commissioner’s Office can be reached [<https://ico.org.uk/>].  If you are in Switzerland, please check [<https://www.edoeb.admin.ch/edoeb/en/home.html>].

We have appointed GDPR-Rep.eu as our EU Representative according to Art 27 GDPR. If you want to make use of your GDPR data privacy rights, please visit: <https://gdpr-rep.eu/q/16452617>

    GDPR-Rep.eu  
    Maetzler Rechtsanwalts GmbH & Co KG  
    Attorneys at Law  
    c/o User Interviews Inc.  
    Schellinggasse 3/10, 1010 Vienna, Austria

    Please add the following subject to all correspondence: GDPR-REPID: 16452617

Researcher-Affiliated Participants:  If you are a Researcher-Affiliated Participant, please contact the applicable Researcher with requests related to your information.  We are not a“controller” of the Personal Information of Researcher-Affiliated Participants,and will pass any requests along to the Researchers, but cannot respond to your requests directly.  We do not control or own Personal Information of Researcher-Affiliated Participants, and only process such Personal Information on behalf of the Researcher with whom you are affiliated. In such cases, we process Personal Information in accordance with our agreements with Researchers and to the extent necessary to comply with applicable law.  To the extent instructed by a Researcher and in accordance with applicable law, we will reasonably assist a Researcher to comply with Participant requests by providing relevant information and support to the particular Researcher to enable it to comply with the request.

 **Your Acknowledgments**

By using our Services, you agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service. You also agree that you assume all risks regarding your use of the Services, transmissions made over the Internet generally, and your sharing of your Personal or Other Information.

By using our Services, you grant us and all other persons or entities involved in the operation of our Services the right to receive, transmit, monitor,retrieve, store and use your Personal or Other Information, including information that may be privileged or confidential under applicable laws, in connection with the operation of our Services and our maintenance of your Personal or Other Information, as described in this Privacy Policy.

 **Policy Changes**

We may make changes to this Policy from time to time. We will post the revised Policy on the website with an “effective date” that indicates when the revised Policy will take effect. We encourage you to review this page periodically to note any changes.

 **Questions or Comments**

If you have any questions or comments regarding our privacy practices or this Privacy Policy, please send us an email at support@userinterviews.com or contact us by mail at: 

User Interviews, Inc  
320 7th Ave, #254  
Brooklyn, NY 11215
